# Daniel Kneipp

Artificial Intelligence Developer

#### Contact

♥ 119 Gloriosa st., Belo Horizonte, MG 305190-490, Brazil



+55 (31) 9-9605 3234 daniel.kneipp@ outlook.com



in://daniel-kneipp github://DanielKneipp gitlab://DanielKneipp

### Languages

Brazilian Portuguese
[Mother tongue]
English
[Professional working
proficiency]

### **Programming**

C++, Python, R, JavaScript, Matlab, Java, Bash

### **Skills**

Machine Learning:



● ● ● ○ ○ Computer Vision:

••••

Text Mining:

### **About me**

I am objective and focused on results. With entrepreneurship in my veins, I spent many years studying and learning, from Convolutional Neural Networks to SWOT Analysis and Nash Equilibrium, trying to make a difference. I know that it looks like a Miss Universe candidate speech asking for world peace (joke), but I really work hard to do something that can change the game. Please, checkout my code repository (https://github.com/DanielKneipp) to see some cool stuff.

### **Education**

2016-2018 Master of Science

Federal University of Minas Gerais (UFMG)

My research area is DNA Computing. The objective is to propose functional chemical circuits for classification tasks using Chemical Reaction Networks theory as a programming language and DNA strands as the hardware. I'm a NanoComp lab. Member (http://www.nanocomp.dcc.ufmg.br/).

2012–2015 **Bachelor** of Science

Federal University of Viçosa (UFV)

I received Presidente Bernardes Medal for my academic excellence (85.4/100). Final Paper: A Genetic Algorithm for Multi-Component Optimization Problems: The Case of the Travelling Thief Problem.

2010–2011 **Technician's** Degree

SENAI School

I Studied the basics of Computer Architecture, Software Development and Network Infrastructure.

#### **Independent** Courses

- Deep Learning Google | Udacity
- Machine Learning Stanford University | Coursera

### **Experience**

#### **Full Time**

2017-Now Research and Development Analyst

MOST Specialist Technologies

Main activities:

- Clustering and analysis of textual medical records;
- · Document classification based on its textual content;
- · Modular deployment of solutions using Docker.

### **Part Time**

#### 2016-2017 Research Program

Invent Vision

Deep Learning research for Computer Vision applications. Implementation of a set of tools to speedup the development (including synthetic dataset generation) and deployment of image classifiers. Application deployment in embedded systems (Nvidia Jetson). Project name: Smart monitoring system by georeferenced images for railways applications.

2015–2016 **Trainee** Invent Vision

Research and implantation of distributed computing systems (based on Hadoop and Spark), developing simple applications made to run across clusters.

2013-2014 Undergraduate Research

Invent Vision

Development of an efficient drowsiness detector based on face expressions (using face and eye tracking algorithms). Deployment made on x86 computers and ARM embedded systems. Project name: System for photometric inspection and automated adjustment of vehicle headlights. Project funded by CNPq (National Council for Scientific and Technological Development).

### awards

2011 **Postgraduate Scholarship** School of Business, The University of California Awarded to the top student in their final year of a Bachelors degree. Mastered the art of filing accurate TPS reports.

### communication skills

2011 **Oral Presentation** California Business Conference Presented the research I conducted for my Masters of Commerce degree.

2010 **Poster**Annual Business Conference, Oregon

As part of the course work for BUS320, I created a poster analyzing several local businesses and presented this at a conference.

### interests

**professional:** data analysis, company profiling, risk analysis, economics, web design, web app creation, software design, marketing **personal:** piano, chess, cooking, dancing, running

### publications

### article in peer-reviewed journal

Electronic Sensors for Assessing Interactions between Healthcare Workers and Patients under Airborne Precautions

Jean-Christophe Lucet, Cédric Laouenan, Guillaume Chelius, Nicolas Veziris, Didier Lepelletier, Adrien Friggeri, Dominique Abiteboul, Elisabeth Bouvet, France Mentré, Eric Fleury *PLoS ONE 7.5 (May 2012)* e37893. 2012

Reconstructing Social Interactions Using an unreliable Wireless Sensor Network

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury, Antoine Fraboulet, France Mentré, Jean-Christophe Lucet

Computer Communications 34.5 (Apr. 2011) pp. 609-618. Elsevier, 2011

#### A Real-World Spreading Experiment in the Blogosphere

Adrien Friggeri, Jean-Philippe Cointet, Matthieu Latapy Complex Systems 19.3 (2011). Complex Systems Publications, Inc., 2011

#### hooks

Microformats: Empowering Your Markup for Web 2.0

John Allsop

Publisher, 2007, Londor

### international peer-reviewed conferences/proceedings

#### Egomunities, Exploring Socially Cohesive Person-based Communities

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

NetSci 2011 The International School and Conference on Network Science, 2011, Budapest, Hongrie

# Fellows: Crowd-sourcing the evaluation of an overlapping community model based on the cohesion measure

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

Interdisciplinary Workshop on Information and Decision in Social Networks, 2011, Cambridge, États-Unis

# Fellows: Crowd-sourcing the evaluation of an overlapping community model based on the cohesion measure

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

Complex Dynamics of Human Interactions, 2011, Vienna, Autriche

#### Triangles to Capture Social Cohesion

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

Third IEEE International Conference on Social Computing, 2011, Cambridge, États-Unis

# Electronic Sensors for Measuring Interactions between Healthcare Workers (HCWs) and Patients (Pts): the Case of Tuberculosis (TB)

Jean-Christophe Lucet, Guillaume Chelius, Cédric Laouenan, Adrien Friggeri, N. Veziris, D. Lepelletier, D. Abiteboul, Elisabeth Bouvet, Eric Fleury, France Mentré

2010 Interscience Conference on Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 2010, Boston, États-Unis

### local peer-reviewed conferences/proceedings

#### Communautés : Arrêtons de ne compter que les arêtes

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

13es Rencontres Francophones sur les Aspects Algorithmiques de Télécommunications (AlgoTel), 2011, Cap Estérel. France

#### Trouver des communautés socialement cohésives est NP-dur

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

13emes journées Graphes et Algorithmes, 2011, Lyon, France

#### Biais dans les mesures obtenues par un réseau de capteurs sans fil

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius

12èmes Rencontres Francophones sur les Aspects Algorithmiques de Télécommunications (AlgoTel), 2010, Belle Dune, France

### other publications

#### Des triangles pour mesurer la cohésion sociale : Fellows, une expérimentation sur Facebook

Adrien Friggeri, Eric Fleury Séminaire w2s @ La Cantine, 2011

### research reports

#### Finding cohesive communities with C<sup>3</sup>

Adrien Friggeri, Eric Fleury

Rapport de recherche RR-7947, 2012

### Egomunities, Exploring Socially Cohesive Person-based Communities

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury

Rapport de recherche RR-7535, 2011

#### Triangles to Capture Social Cohesion

Adrien Friggeri, Guillaume Chelius, Eric Fleury Rapport de recherche RR-7686, 2011

### Maximizing the Cohesion is NP-hard

Adrien Friggeri, Eric Fleury
Rapport de recherche RR-7734, 2011